# **Matthew Church**

churchmf@gmail.com 778-996-2257 matthewchurch.ca

Summary

Software Engineer / Computing Scientist with a passion for game design. Experienced Java, C++, and C# programmer with knowledge in operating system concepts, algorithms, user-interface design, database integration, data processing, multi-platform tool development, 3D animation and computer graphics.

Experience

## Software Engineer I

**Electronic Arts Canada, Burnaby** 

July 2013 – Current

C++, ActionScript

Full time engineer on the FIFA Games Mode Team. Working extensively with producers, quality assurance and other engineers to deliver high quality features for the game. Participated in agile sprint planning in a large team in order to meet deliverable on a deadline. Tested, wrote and debugged C++ and ActionScript in a massive code base.

#### **Associate Software Engineer**

**Electronic Arts Canada, Burnaby** 

January 2012 - September 2012

C++, SQL

Internship on the FIFA Games Mode Team. Worked extensively with producers, quality assurance and other engineers to deliver high quality features for the game. Took ownership of several features both new and old. Tested, wrote and debugged C++ and SQL in a massive code.

#### **Programmer Analyst Research Assistant**

**Department of Psychology, University of Alberta** 

September 2011 – January 2012

C++, Source Engine, 3DS Max 2010

Programmer Analyst working with Valve's Source engine to develop cognitive psychology simulations testing spatial awareness, memory, and navigation in virtual environments.

#### **Software Engineer Intern**

ScriptEase Research Project, University of Alberta

May 2010 – September 2011

Java, C++, Aurora Toolset, Galaxy Editor

Developed and implemented extendable tools in a team environment which allow users to script video games without any programming experience. Attended weekly meetings emphasizing scrum planning, feature development and brainstorming. The code base grew to just over 12 000 lines during my time on the project.

**Projects** 

#### "Aporkalypse" - Great Canadian Appathon 3 Entry

October 2012 C#, XNA

Designed and implemented a mobile game for Windows Phone 7 in 48 hours for the Great Canadian Appathon 3. Placed in the top 25 and won the category for Best Windows Phone 7 Application.

## "Umpire Strikes Back" - Great Canadian Appathon 2 Entry

October 2011 C#, XNA

Designed and implemented a mobile game for Windows Phone 7 in 48 hours for the Great Canadian Appathon 2. Placed in the top 25 and won the category for Best Original/Experimental Application.

## "Project Origin" – 3D Game Engine

November 2010 - December 2010

C++, OpenGL

Designed and implemented over two weeks. Able to load in any OBJ 3D model and manipulate them in an environment with line-plane collision and basic physics.

## **ORTS: Hierarchical Combat AI Template**

November 2009 – December 2009

C++

Designed and implemented a high level real time strategy framework to facilitate artificial intelligence programming in the ORTS game engine. This multi-level approach abstracted combat to allow for easier algorithmic unit micro, squad formations and army macro.

**Accredited Titles** 

FIFA 13 Xbox 360, PS3, PC FIFA 14 Xbox 360, PS3, PC 2014 FIFA World Cup Brazil Xbox 360, PS3

Education

## **BSc, Computing Science Specialization**

2007 - 2013

**University of Alberta** 

Honours and Awards

Academic Excellence Scholarship Technical Achievement Best Original/Experimental Application Best Windows Phone 7 Application University of Alberta
University of Alberta 2009 Game Development Awards
Great Canadian Appathon 2
Great Canadian Appathon 3

**Hobbies and Activities** 

Video Game Artwork and Design Club Global Game Jam Fragapalooza Annual LAN Party Recreational Soccer, Basketball, Volleyball University of Alberta Vancouver, British Columbia Edmonton, Alberta Edmonton, Alberta

References on request